# Yeo Kang Nian

Mobile: + 65 93666950 Email: <u>yeokangnian@gmail.com</u>

Linkedin Profile: https://sg.linkedin.com/in/kang-nian-yeo-1a260924

#### **SUMMARY**

Kang Nian is a CPA with over 11 years of experience in budgeting and forecasting, financial planning, analytics, accounting, consultancy, project management experience and investment financing across various sectors of which approximately 3.5 years was in Japan. He is commercially astute and is operationally hands on without losing sight of the big picture.

He is currently working as a VP - Finance in L Capital Asia, a private equity arm of LVMH group. He has financed over USD 700m of investments in iconic brands such as Crystal Jade, Dr Wu, Marubi, 2XU, Seafolly, RM Williams, etc. In his course of work, he has oversight of portfolio monitoring, validate the valuation of each of the company, fund administration, setting up of fund structures. Prior to that, he worked for Commerzbank (Singapore), leading the management reporting/financial planning and analysis team for Asia. Before that, he was working for Deutsche Bank (Japan) as an AVP – Cost Analytics.

He has previously achieved a global CFO award with Deutsche Bank for cost reduction and operational efficiency proposal. He is effectively bilingual in Mandarin and English with Japanese conversational skills. Kang Nian is currently taking a part-time EMBA from Nanyang Technological University and is expected to graduate in 2017.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## L Capital Singapore Pte Ltd. (Private equity arm of LVMH Group)

Vice President, Finance (Singapore)

March 2013 to date

- Reporting to the CFO, spearheaded the completion and financing of investments of more than USD 700 million into iconic deals across AsiaPacific such as Crystal Jade and Ce La Vi from Singapore, Dr Wu from Taiwan, Marubi from China, 2XU, Seafolly and RM Williams from Australia, etc.
- Oversight of accounting (IFRS), fund administration, management report and treasury function as Controller of 2 investment funds totaling USD 1.6 billion.
- Ensuring tax, statutory, legal and other regulations compliance are met.
- Oversight of portfolio monitoring reports which analysis each brands' profit and loss and ultimately validate their valuation.

#### Commerzbank AG

Vice President, Deputy Head of Controlling Asia (Singapore)

August 2011 to February 2013

- Reporting to the Finance Director, led a 3person management reporting team to align and improved the reporting format, analysis and commentary level of the management reports to enable faster flow in decision making of department heads in Investment Banking, Corporate Banking and Support Functions.
- Responsible for co-ordination and preparation of consolidated budget for Asia Pacific.
- Responsible for KPI management report for support functions and front offices (trading, treasury and corporate finance).
- Business partnering with various divisional heads to analysis their P&L.

#### **Deutsche Bank**

Assistant Vice President, Cost Analytics (Singapore) Assistant Vice President, Cost Analytics (Tokyo, Japan) January 2011 to July 2011 August 2009 to December 2010

- DB Group CFO Star Award Individual Winner 2010 for introduction of cost reduction and operational efficiency plan.
- Successfully implemented cost reports with value based matrix for executive management, which enhanced cost transparency and provided proposals for management decisions.
- Cost Controlling, budgeting and forecast function for DB Japan Group.

## KPMG Business Assurance Co., Ltd

Associate Consultant (Tokyo, Japan)

August 2007 to June 2009

- Seconded to Goldman Sachs Realty Japan Ltd for 1.5 year period as sole consultant to assist the client in successful implementation of Activity Based Accounting project.
- Assisted Goldman Sachs Realty Japan Ltd in back office outsourcing financial planning, analysis and budgeting.

## Kintetsu World Express (S) Pte Ltd

Assistant Accountant (Singapore)

April 2006 to April 2007

- Led a 1 person team in management reporting function for Singapore
- Performed profit and loss analysis for each individual division
- Performed cost allocation to each division.

#### **BDO LLP**

Audit Assistant (Singapore)

June 2005 to April 2006

• Involved in audit of Bodyshop, Beiersdorf (Nivea) and financial due diligence - IPO assessment of a construction company as well as cross-border audit in Malaysia and China.

## **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATION**

# Nanyang Technological University, Nanyang Business School

Executive MBA (part-time)

Expected Graduation 2017

CPA (Australia)

Since 2008

# **Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology**

Bachelors in Business (Accountancy)

2001 - 2005

### Language Skills

English – Native Mandarin – Native

Japanese – Conversational